Contact

erinpjaynes@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/erin-jaynes-20636632 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Hospitals Healthcare Nursing

Erin Jaynes

SVP/ System CNO at Franciscan Alliance, Inc.

South Bend, Indiana

Summary

Erin Jaynes has over 30 years of advanced clinical experience as a Registered Nurse and Hospital Executive. Her expertise within the industry encompasses hospital operations, strategic planning, performance improvement, designing or retrofitting clinical campuses for future growth, patient throughput, clinical effectiveness, bed management and nursing leadership. Prior to joining Franciscan Alliance, inc., Erin worked as a Senior Manager/ Specialist Leader at Deloitte for over 5 years working across the United States and Internationally. Erin also previously worked as a VP/ CNE for a 794 bed acute care facility part of an 11 hospital system.

Experience

Franciscan Alliance, Inc. SVP/ System CNO July 2017 - Present (3 years 1 month)

Mishawaka, Indiana

Senior Vice President/System Chief Nursing Officer for Franciscan Alliance Health System. Providing executive nurse leadership across the health system. In addition to Nursing leadership oversight, I am also responsible for the system Logistic Center including bed management and the transfer center for the health system as well as executive leadership of Hospice and Home Care and DME across Franciscan Alliance.

Deloitte

5 years 6 months

Senior Manager/ Specialist Leader August 2015 - July 2017 (2 years)

Greater Detroit Area

Lead clinical transformation efforts across academic and not for profit health care systems. Provide expertise to conduct Assessment, Design/Implementation across the following areas: Productivity/Labor workforce, Perioperative Services, Emergency Services, Care Management, Bed

Management, Patient Throughput, Float Pool, Ambulatory Clinics, Funds Flow and Administrative Spend, Operating Model design and Organization structure design and implementation

Manager, Consulting LLP February 2012 - August 2015 (3 years 7 months) Detroit

Manage large scale strategy and operation projects within Heath Sciences. Focused leadership on hospital operations projects.

ProMedica
Vice-President/CNO
December 2004 - November 2011 (7 years)
Toledo, Ohio

Fiscal and operational responsibility for Medical-surgical, Intermediate, Critical Care, Labor and Delivery, Post- Partum, Psychiatry, Emergency Center, and Urgent Care Center. In addition to multiple out-patient services including Fertility Center, Maternal Fetal Medicine, Midwifery clinics, Women's services, Indigent care clinic and an Orthopedic clinic.

- Managed direct budget of \$ 7.6 million dollars.
- Fiscal responsibility for budgets totaling \$73 million dollars.
- Oversight of 1500 RN FTE's

Medical College of Ohio
Administrative Nurse Specialist
December 2000 - December 2004 (4 years 1 month)
Toledo, Ohio

Oversight of Nursing Administrative functions for a large University Health system. Responsible for a 300 FTE float pool, JCAHO coordination, Staff development, patient throughput and nursing payroll. Developed an electronic patient throughput process that decreased EMS bypass hours to less than 1%. Implemented an internal agency utilizing current hospital nursing staff that eliminated all outside agency staff saving over \$5M annually.

Education

Medical College of Ohio MSN, Nursing (1990 - 1992)